In line with longstanding initiatives to expand its green spaces, New York City is planting tens of thousands of trees each year.
为了配合扩大绿地的长期计划，纽约市每年都种植数以万计的树木。
They provide shade, lower surface temperatures, absorb a surprising amount of airborne carbon, remove tiny pollutants, and provide wildlife habitat along with just plain beauty.
它们提供树荫，降低地表温度，吸收数量惊人的空气中的碳，清除微小的污染物，为野生动物提供栖息地，同时还带来纯粹的美感。
Something could go wrong, though, according to a new study.
不过，根据一项新研究，这件事也可能出问题。
Oaks and sweetgums, which currently account for a majority of the city’s trees, produce huge amounts of a chemical substance called isoprene.
橡树和枫香树目前占该市树木的大多数，它们会产生大量一种叫作异戊二烯的化学物质。
Harmless by itself, isoprene interacts rapidly with polluting nitrogen oxides released by vehicles, buildings and industry to form ground-level ozone — a major factor in many breathing problems.
异戊二烯本身无害，但它会与车辆、建筑和工业排放的污染性氮氧化物迅速发生反应，生成近地面臭氧——这是导致许多呼吸问题的主要因素。
The research, carried out by scientists at the Columbia Climate School and other institutions, found that if the city maintains past species patterns in new plantings, isoprene production in Manhattan in coming decades will go up by about 140%, and resulting summer ozone levels as much as 30%.
这项由哥伦比亚大学气候学院及其他机构的科学家开展的研究发现，如果该市在新种植中沿用过去的树种结构，未来几十年曼哈顿的异戊二烯产量将增加约140%，由此导致的夏季臭氧水平最多会上升30%。
“We’re all for planting more trees.
“我们完全赞成多种树。
They bring so many good things,” said study coauthor Róisín Commane.
树木带来了那么多好处，”该研究的合著者罗伊辛·康曼说。
“But if we’re not careful, we could make air quality worse.”
“但如果我们不小心，就可能让空气质量变得更糟。”
The Parks Department is not oblivious to the issue.
公园管理局并非没有意识到这个问题。
A study carried out by some of its researchers several years ago concluded that city trees did release isoprene.
几年前该局部分研究人员开展的一项研究就得出结论：城市树木确实会释放异戊二烯。
“We didn’t make a big deal of that,” said Novem Auyeung, a Parks Department senior scientist.
“我们当时没把这当回事，”公园管理局的资深科学家诺文·欧阳说。
She said trees should not be viewed as the enemy.
她说，不应该把树木视为敌人。
“We could plant any trees we want to, if we just rethink our car-centric lifestyle,” she said.
“只要我们重新审视以汽车为中心的生活方式，我们想种什么树都可以，”她说。
“We’re not going to go cutting down any big old oaks,” and neither will the department completely stop planting new ones, said Auyeung.
“我们不会去砍掉任何高大的老橡树，”欧阳说，管理局也不会完全停止种植新的橡树。
“You have to think about what you would lose if you do that.”
“你得想想，如果那样做，你会失去什么。”
Oaks are keystone species, she pointed out, providing food and habitat for native insects, birds and other animals.
她指出，橡树是关键物种，为本地的昆虫、鸟类和其他动物提供食物和栖息地。